Inventory of the James A. Bill Papers 1940-2003
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Documents Concerning the Bilderberg Meetings, 1980-1988
  - Bilderberg Group Meetings and Steering Conferences 1980 - 1988 (2)
    - (2, 27)
      - Bilderberg Group 1981 (2, 27)
        - (2, 27)
          - Ball, George. Obstacle to the Effective Coordination of Western Policies. 3/24/1981 (2, 27)
          - Prepared by: Hon. Toon, Malcolm. Dealing with the Soviet Union in the 1980’s. for Bilderberg Meeting, 5/14 - 17/1981. Lucerne, Switzerland. (2, 27)
          - Prepared by: Stein, Herbert Dr. Economic Problems of the Industrial Democracies: A View for the United States. For Bilderberg Meeting, 5/14 - 17/1981. Lucerne, Switzerland. (2, 27)
          - Prepared by: George Ball. Obstacles to the Effective Coordination of Western Policies. For Bilderberg Meeting. 5/14 - 17/1981. Lucerne, Switzerland. (2, 27)
          - Prepared by: Herrhausen, Alfred Dr. How Can the Western Economies Put Their House in Order? For the Bilderberg Meeting, 5/14 - 17/1981. Lucerne, Switzerland. (2, 27)
          - Prepared by: Hon. Denis W. Healey. R[u]ssia and the West in the Eighties. For Bilderberg Meeting, 5/14 - 17/1981 (2, 27)
          - Koester, Mary E. Wire to George Ball. 5/12/1981 (2, 27)
          - Bilderberg Meeting. Burgenstock, Switzerland 5/15 - 17/1981: Plane and arrival schedule (2, 27)
          - Transport arrangements (2, 27)
          - Koester, Mary E. Wire to Ritz Hotel, Paris France. 5/13/1981 (2, 27)
          - Ball, George W. Wire to Stockholm Sweden. Attn: Mr. Bernt L. Junggren. (2, 27)
          - Koester, Mary. Wire to George Ball (2, 27)
          - Koester, Mary. Wire to George Ball. 4/28/1981 (2, 27)
          - Scheel, Walter. Invitation to George Ball. 2/1981 (2, 27)
          - Halberstadt, Victor. Letter to the authors of Working Papers for the Burgenstock Conference. 4/27/1981 (2, 27)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Provisional List of Participants. 4/27/1981 (2, 27)
          - Bundy, Walter. Letter to George Ball. 4/23/1981 (2, 27)
          - Hoogendoorn, Anne. Letter to the Steering Committee. 4/22/1981 (2, 27)
            - Steering Committee Meeting Agenda. Burgenstock. 5/14/1981 (2, 27)
            - Provisional Timetable (2, 27)
            - Chair persons (2, 27)
          - Koester, Mary. Wire to Anne Hoogendoor and Victor Halberstadt. 4/21/1981 (2, 27)
          - Guardsman Travel Agency Inc. Invoice for George Ball. 4/17/1981 (2, 27)
            - Receipt (2, 27)
          - Halberstadt, Victor. Letter to George Ball. 4/10/1981 (2, 27)
          - Halberstadt, Victor and Paul Finney. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 4/16/1981 (2, 27)
          - Getchell, Charles. Letter to Victor Halberstadt. 3/26/1981 (2, 27)
            - Note From Charles Getchell’s Letter to the Steering Committee during the Vienna Meeting (10/31/1980) (2, 27)
          - Muller, Charles. Letter to U.S. and Canadian Participants in the Bilderberg Meeting at Burgenstock, 5/1981. 5/23/1981 (2, 27)
            - Provisional List of Participants. 5/16/1981 (2, 27)
          - Ball, George. Letter to Walter Scheel. 3/21/1981 (2, 27)
          - Heinz, Henry J. II. Letter to David T. Schiff. 3/11/1981 (2, 27)
          - Schiff, David T. Letter to Henry J. Heinz II. 3/3/1981 (2, 27)
          - Finney, Paul B. Letter to George Ball. 2/25/1981 (2, 27)
          - Halberstadt, Victor and Paul Finney. Letter to Steering Committee. 2/18/1981: program (2, 27)
            - Bilderberg Meeting. List of Participants (2, 27)
          - Finney, Paul. Letter to the American Members of the International Steering Committee. 1/26/1981 (2, 27)
            - Summary Agenda 1/23/1981 (2, 27)
          - Giamatti, Bartlett A. Letter to Paul B. Finney. 1/16/1981 (2, 27)
          - Finney, Paul B. Letter to George Ball. 1/5/1981 (2, 27)
        - (2, 27, 3)
          - Eliot, Theodore L. Letter to the American Members of the Bilderberg Steering Committee. 12/9/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Address - List Members of the Steering Committee. 10/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Scheel, Walter. Letter to Theodore L. Eliot Jr. 11/23/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Provisional Agenda - Sandefjord Conference. 5/14 - 16/1982: Topic: “Tension in European - American Relations” (2, 27, 3)
            - Sadefjord Conference - 5/14 - 16/1982. Invited Participants 12/9/1982. (2, 27, 3)
            - Addresses Members Advisory Group (2, 27, 3)
          - Bilderberg Meeting compliments. 11/25/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Hoogendoorn, Anne. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 9/28/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Steering Committee Meeting. Agenda. 10/30/1981. Westbury Hotel, New York. (2, 27, 3)
            - Bilderberg Meeting. Minutes of the Meeting Held by the Steering Committee. Burgenstock, Switzerland. 3/14/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Eliot, Ted, Andrew Knight and Ted Sommer. 6/4/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Proposal for Graphical Distribution of Participants 1982 Meeting. Burgenstock 1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Suggested Topics and Authors for Norway Meeting (2, 27, 3)
          - Hoogendoorn, Anne. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 11/16/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Minutes of the Meeting Held by the Steering Committee. New York. USA. 10/30/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Itinerary. Mr. and Mrs. George Ball. 4/20/1981 - 5/18/1981. (2, 27, 3)
          - Revised 3/25/1981 and sent to P. Finney (2, 27, 3)
            - Ball, George. Obstacles to the Effective Coordination of Western Policies. 3/24/1981[2 Copies] (2, 27, 3)
          - Scheel, Walter. Letter to George Ball. 5/20/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Kelly, Bernard. Telegraph Copy to George Ball. 4/28/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Bilderberg Meeting. Provisional List of Participants. 3/27/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Halberstadt, Victor. Paul B. Finney. Letter to the authors of Working papers for the Burgenstock Conference. 4/27/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Halberstadt, Victor and Paul Finney. Letter to the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 4/22/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Steering Committee Meeting. Agenda. Burgenstock. 5/14/1981 (2, 27, 3)
            - Provisional Timetable (2, 27, 3)
          - Hurford, Lee. Letter to Charles Muller. 6/16/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Ball, George. Obstacles to the Effective Coordination of Western Policies. 6/16/1981 [Revised by Charles Muller] (2, 27, 3)
          - Koester, Mary. Cable to the Hague (Netherlands) concerning Bilderberg Meeting (2, 27, 3)
          - Bilderberg Meeting Arrival plan for George Ball. (2, 27, 3)
          - Ball, George. Letter to Walter Scheel. 3/21/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Notice to Participants. Burgenstock, Switzerland. 5/15 - 17/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Scheel, Walter. Invitation to George Ball. 2/1981: concerning Lucerne, Switzerland Meeting (2, 27, 3)
          - Heinz, Henry. Letter to David T. Schiff. 3/11/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Finney, Paul B. Letter to George Ball. 2/25/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Finney, Paul. Letter to the American Members of the International Steering Committee. 1/26/1981:Concerning Bilderberg Meeting (2, 27, 3)
            - Summary Agenda as of 1/23/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Giamatti, Bartletti A. Letter to Paul B. Finney. 1/16/1981 (2, 27, 3)
          - Finney, Paul. Letter to George Ball. 1/5/1981 (2, 27, 3)
        Subseries 3: Bilderberg Group, Steering Committee and Articles and Publicity in 1982
      - Bilderberg Group, Steering Committee and Articles and Publicity in 1982 (2, 27, 3)
        - (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - George Ball, Itinerary. London, Brussels. 10/19 - 24/1982: Bilderberg Meeting Highlighted. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Address - List of Members of the Steering Committee and Members of Advisory Group. 10/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Steering Committee Meeting Participants. Brussels, Belgium on October 23, 1982. 10/21/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Hoogendoor, Anne. Letter to the International Steering Committee. 5/19/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Final List of Participants. Sandefjord, Norway. 5/14 - 16/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Secretariat of the Meeting address and conference address, 1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Provisional Agenda. Sandefjord Conference. 5/14 - 16/1982: Topic: “Tension in European - American Relations” (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Primary Program 1982 Conference. 3/16/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Heinz, H. J. Letter to George Ball. 8/30/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Check written by George Ball. To American Friends of Bilderberg for $3,000. 11/26/1982 [Copy] (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Peterson, Peter. Letter to Henry J. Heinz II.10/ 29/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Receipt for $2500 to American Friends of Bilderberg Group. 10/25/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Heinz, H. J. Address [copy of letter] (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Hurfor, Lee. ( Assistant to George Ball) Telegraph to Anne Hoogendoorn. 10/6/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Hoogendoorn, Anne. Letter to the International Steering Committee. 5/19/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Members of the Steering Committee. 7/1/1981 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Members of the Advisory Group (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Ball, George. Memo to “Mary” 6/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Duisenberg, W. F. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee. 4/16/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Estimated Costs for the financial years 1982/1985 (Dutch Guilders) (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Proposed contributions for the financial years 1982/1985 (Dutch Gulders) (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Travel Card for Norway Conference. George Ball. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Invitation to George Ball. 3/3/1982: concerning Sanderjord, Norway Conference. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Eliot, Theodore. Letter to George Ball. 5/19/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Hurford, Lee. Telegraph to Park Hotel in Sanderjord, Norway. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Secretariat of the Meeting. Correspondences address and conference address (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Preliminary Program for 1982 Conference. 3/16/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Provisional Agenda. Sandefjord Conference. 5/14 - 16/1982. (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Eliot, Theodore. Letter to the U.S. Members of the International Steering Committee and Members of the Advisory Group (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Steering Committee Meeting. Agenda. Park Hotel. 5/13/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Provisional Timetable (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Provisional Agenda (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Changes in and Composition of Membership of Steering Committee (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Travel Card for George Ball. (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Hurford, Lee. Telegram to Anne Walford (secretary to Mr. Luind) 5/04/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Minutes of the Meeting held by the Steering Committee. Sandefjord, Norway. 5/13/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Note from Mary to George Ball: concerning Bilderberg Meeting location (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Scanticon - Princeton, Conference and Hotel Center Brochure (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Travel Card for George Ball to Norway Conference (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Eliot, Theodore L. Letter to the American Members of the Bilderberg Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 9/27/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Possible U.S. Participants. Montebello Meeting (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Notes [Handwritten]: Hilton International, Brussells (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Hoogendoorn, Anne. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee. 11/9/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Minutes of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Hilton International. 10/23/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Speech at Bilderberg Meeting. 10/23/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - List of dinner invites to Baron Lamberts. 10/22/1982. [in French] (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Tentative List of American Invites to Montebello Meeting. 10/23/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Tentative List of American Invites to Montebello Meeting cont. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Tentative Outline for Topics and Authors: Overall Topic: Trade, Aid, Politics and the Atlantic Alliance (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Program. Steering Committee. 10/22/1982. Brussels (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - List of Suggested Names for Participants 1983 Conference by Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 10/19/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Possible U.S. Participants. Montebello Meeting (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Halberstadt, Victor and Ted Eliot. Letter to the Steering Committee. 9/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - List of Confirmed Attendees Brussels Meeting. 9/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Agenda. Steering Committee Meeting. Hilton Hotel on 10/23/1982. 9/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Minutes of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Sandefjord, Norway. 5/13/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Report to the Steering Committee Bilderberg from a Sub - Committee struck to scrutinize the proceedings at the Sandefjord meeting on May 14 - 16, 1982, and to recommend any changes in procedures. 7/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Halberstadt, Victor and Ted Eliot. Letter to the Steering Committee. 9/15/1982: Tentative Program 1983 Conference. (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Tentative Outline for Topics and Authors: Overall Topic: Trade, Aid, Politics and the Atlantic Alliance. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the Steering Committee. 9/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - List of Confirmed attendees Brussels Meeting. 9/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Agenda. Steering Committee Meeting. Hilton Hotel. 10/23/1982. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Minutes of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Sandefjord, Norway. 5/13/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Halberstadt, Victor and Ted Eliot. Letter to the Steering Committee. 9/15/1982: Tentative Program 1983 Conference. (2, 27, 3, 4)
            - Tentative outline for topics and authors. (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Report to the Steering Committee Bilderberg from a sub - Committee struck to scrutinize the proceedings on 5/14 - 16/1982. Sandefjord. 7/15/1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Geographical Distribution of Participants in 1983 Meeting. Sandefjord Meeting 1982 (2, 27, 3, 4)
          - Karpel, Craig S. The Gnomes of Bilderberg. from Penthouse.145+ (2, 27, 3, 4)
        Subseries 4: Bilderberg Meeting, Steering Committee 1983
      - Bilderberg Meeting, Steering Committee 1983 (2, 27, 4)
        - (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the Participants in the 1983 Bilderberg Conference [2 Copies]. (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Bilderberg Conference. Preliminary Program. 1/15/1983[2 Copies] (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Greetings Note from The Hague (Netherlands) (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Halberstadt, Victor. Letter to Helmut Schmidt. 11/12/1982 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the American Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 11/1/1982 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - American Committee Invitation List (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Vasudeva, Karen. Letter to Anne Hoogendoorn. 10/18/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the U.S. Steering Committee and Advisory Council Members. 11/1/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - 1984 Bilderberg Invitation List (those who have not attended Meetings before.) (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Eliot, Theodore. Letter to David Kearns. 11/2/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Autumn in Geneva (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Jordan, Vernon E. Briefing. Bilderberg Steering Committee Meeting. Eindhoven (the Netherlands). 10/15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Theodore. Letter to the U.S. Participants of Saltsjobaden Meeting. 3/5/1984 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Thoughts on the U.S. and Europe. 1/4/1984 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Theodore. Letter to the Members of the U.S. Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 2/3/1984 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Bilderberg Meeting. Provisional Program 1984 Conference. Saltsjobaden (Sweden), 5/11 - 13/1984. 1/17/1984 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Provisional List of Participants. Saltsjobaden Conference. 5/11 - 13/1984. 1/24/1984 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Compliments from the Secretariat. 1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
              Series 1: Meetings of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Hotel Cocagne, Eindhoven. 10/15/1983.
            - Meetings of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Hotel Cocagne, Eindhoven. 10/15/1983. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Dekker, W. Letter to George Ball. 8/8/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Halberstadt, Victor and Ted Eliot. Letter to the Steering Committee and Advisory Group: concerning Eindhoven Meeting. 10/14 - 15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Muller, Charles. Letter to George Ball. 6/16/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Donahue, Thomas. Medium Term Prospects for Growth in the World Economy: The Prospects of Full Employment. Bilderberg Conference. 5/12 - 15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - General Information. Le Chateau Montebello. Quebec, Canada. 5/13 - 15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Final List with Addresses of Participants. Le Chateau Montebello, Canada. 5/13 - 15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Leber, George, Alois Mertes. Letter to His Excellency the Archbishop John Robert Roach. 3/14/1983. (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Alphabetical List of Participants with Room Numbers. Montebello. 5/12 - 15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Maps of Le Chateau Montebello (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Bilderberg Meeting. Programme. (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Departures from Hilton Hotel, Amsterdam. 10/16/1983. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Hoogendoorn, Anne. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Steering Committee Meeting. Hotel De Cocagne, Eindhoven.10/15/1983. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Guest List for dinner party hosted by Dr. W. Dekker. 10/14/1983. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Agenda. Steering Committee Meeting. Hotel De Cocagne, Eindhoven. 10/15/1983. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Bilderberg Topics List (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Halberstadt, Victor and Ted Eliot. Letter to the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 9/20/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - First Thoughts about 1984 Conference Program. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Bennett, Jack and Sten Gustafsson and Andrew Knight. Report on the Montebello Meeting to the Bilderberg Steering Committee. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Prince Bernhard of the Netherlands. Invitation to George Ball. 10/15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Hoogendorn, Anne. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 9/29/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Hurford, Lee G. Letter to Victor Halberstadt. 9/19/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - George Ball. Travel Advisory Form. Bilderberg Steering Committee Meeting. 10/14/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to George Ball. 9/1/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to George Ball. 9/8/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the Members of the U.S. Steering Committee and Advisory Council. 8/26/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Hawley, Philip. List of Committees by Industry and Awards (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Bilderberg Meeting. Geographical Distribution of Participants 1984 Meeting. (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Cancellations to Montebello Conference. 5/13 - 15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Changes in Steering Committee Membership (2, 27, 4, 5)
            - Hawley, Philip. List of Committees by Industry and Awards (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - List of Participants of Bilderberg Meeting (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Minutes of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Le Chateau Montebello, Canada. 5/12/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Draft - Agenda. Steering Committee Meetings. Hotel De Cocagne, Eindhoven. 10/15/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
          - Minutes of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Le Chateau Montebello, Canada. 5/12/1983 (2, 27, 4, 5)
        Subseries 5: Bilderberg Meetings 1983
      - Bilderberg Meetings 1983 (2, 27, 5)
        - (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - George Ball Itinerary for 5/12 - 31/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meeting. Chateau Montebello, Canada. 5/12 - 15/1983: Arrival and Departure flight information (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Agenda. Chateau Montebello, Canada. 5/12 - 15/1983: Provisional Agenda as of 4/28/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Note to George Ball. Handwritten Note from Hoogendoorn? (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Provisional List of Participants. Montebello Conference. 4/18/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Travel Advisory Form. Bilderberg Meeting. Le Chateau, Montebello Canada. 5/13 - 15/1983: George Ball (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Notes from Bilderberg meeting [Handwritten] (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Agenda. Steering Committee. Chateau Montebello Canada. 5/12/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Minutes of the Meeting. Steering Committee. Hilton International Hotel, Brussels. 10/23/1982: compiled 11/5/1982 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Changes in the Steering Committee. (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Hoogendorn, Anne (on behalf of Wim Duisenburg, Honorary Treasurer). Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee. 4/15/1983: Financial Results and Estimates (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Estimated Costs for the Financial Years 1983/1986. Steering Committee. 5/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the American Members of the Steering Committee and Advisory Group. 11/1/10982: information (2, 27, 5, 6)
            - American Steering Committee Invitation List (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bialer, Seweryn. The Soviet Union and the West in the 1980s: Containment, Détente or Confrontation. Bilderberg Conference 1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bialer, Seweryn. The Andropov succession. (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Saturday Morning Session [program]: Medium Term Prospects for Growth in the World Economy, the future of world trade. (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meeting Notes[Handwritten] (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Lamfalussy, Alexandre. Saturday Afternoon Session [Program]: Medium Term Prospects for Growth in the World Economy, The West banking System and the International Debt Situation: Facts, History, Prospects and issues. Bilderberg Meetings 1983. (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Center for International Business discussion schedule. 3 pgs (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Flight Travel schedule for 1983 Bilderberg Meeting. (2, 27, 5, 6)
            - Bilderberg Conference Arrival Schedule Outline (2, 27, 5, 6)
            - Provisional List of Participants. (2, 27, 5, 6)
            - General Information. 4 pgs. (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Arnold, Carol [for T. E. Eliot, Honorary Secretary - General for the U.S.] Memorandum to U. S. Participants in the 1983 Bilderberg Meetings, Chateau Montebello, Canada (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Arnold, Carol. Letter to the U.S. participants in 1983 Bilderberg Meeting. 4/26/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Travel Arrangements for Bilderberg [meeting, 1983] (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Hoogendorn, Anne [Secretariat]. Letter to the Members of the Steering Committee. 4/18/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Provisional List of Participants. Montebello Conference. 5/13 - 15/1983: prepared 4/18/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Notes on Bilderberg Meeting [Handwritten] 3/22/1983? (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Travel Advisory Form for Bilderberg Meeting. For George Ball. (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Arnold, Carol [American Friends of Bilderberg, Inc.] Letter to the American Participants in the 1983 Bilderberg Meeting at Chateau Montebello, Canada. 3/25/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Eliot, Ted. Letter to the U.S. Participants in Bilderberg Meeting at Chateau Montebello. 3/9/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)
          - Bilderberg Meetings. Provisional List of Participants. Montebello Conference. 3/3/1983 (2, 27, 5, 6)